A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Wolf scalp bounties records, 1776-1818
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Wolf scalp bounties records, 1776-1818
The Library of Virginia
APA 691
1.05 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
Beginning in 1632 the General Assembly permitted localities to pay rewards to persons who killed wolves. Throughout the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries these laws were amended, repealed, and reenacted. An act passed by the General Assembly during its session begun in October 1778 made the auditor of public accounts responsible for reimbursing localities for destruction of "Noxious Animals," which included wolves.
Scope and Content
The Wolf Scalp Bounties Records, 1776-1818, are arranged alphabetically by county name with oversized materials arranged in the second box. The records include accounts and receipts containing the names of persons to whom payments were made, the amounts, and the dates paid for the wolf scalps. The accounts and receipts were usually certified by the local county clerk.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by county name with oversize arranged in box 2.
Contents List
- Albemarle County, 1784-1797. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Amherst County, 1789-1790. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Augusta County, 1776-1804. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bath County, 1796-1804. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bedford County, 1788-1798. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Berkley County, 1782-1795. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Botetourt County, 1779-1803. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Campbell County, 1788-1790. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Charlotte County, 1786-1792. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fauquier County, 1792-1793. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Frederick County, 1775-1794. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Grayson County, 1794-1805. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Greenbrier County, 1783-1802. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hampshire County, 1776-1809. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Hardy County, 1787-1805. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Harrison County, 1785-1815. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Kanawha County, 1796-1807. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lee County, 1794-1806. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lincoln County, 1784-1792. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Mason County, 1805-1806. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Monongalia County, 1784-1807. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Monroe County, 1800-1804. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Montgomery County, 1786-1818. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Patrick County, 1791-1811. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Pendleton County, 1788-1808. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Pittsylvania County, 1789-1793. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Randolph County, 1788-1805. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Rockbridge County, 1777-1797. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Russell County, 1785-1809. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Shenandoah County, 1779-1809. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Tazewell County, 1801-1807. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Washington County, 1778-1809. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Wood County, 1805. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Wythe County, 1790-1806. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Wrappers and unidentified, 1786. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Oversize, Botetourt County, 1790-1792. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Oversize, Greenbrier County, 1793-1801. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Oversize, Montgomery County, 1786-1801. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Oversize, Ohio County, 1786-1805. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Oversize, Russell County, 1793-1806. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Oversize, Shenandoah County, 1783-1793. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Oversize, Washington County, 1783-1806. (Box 2, Folder 7)